我约你们来吃早午餐
The reason I asked you guys out to brunch...
是因为我一直在想首席伴娘的问题
...is because I've been thinking about my maid of honor.
天啊  这一刻终于到来了
Oh, my God. This is it. Oh.
我希望是你
I really hope it's you.
-我希望是你  -我也希望是我
- I hope it's you. - Me too.
首先  我非常爱你们
First of all, I love you both so much.
-你们都很重要  -废话少说  到底是谁
- You're both so important to me. - Blah, blah, blah. Who is it?
我想  我们可以想出一个办法
I was thinking maybe we could come up with a system...
轮流当彼此的首席伴娘
...where we trade off being maid of honor for each other.
-假设菲比是我的首席伴娘  -太棒了
- Hypothetically, if Phoebe were mine... - Yes! Oh.
那只是假设
Hypothetically.
一样啦
Still.
如果菲比是我的
If Phoebe were mine.
瑞秋是菲比的  我就是瑞秋的
Rachel would be Phoebe's, I'd be Rachel's.
我们都可以当首席伴娘  大家都高兴了
We all get to do it and no one gets upset.
-是个好主意  -可以啊  说吧是谁
- That's a pretty good idea. - I'll do that. So, who's yours?
那是最棒的部分了  你们来决定
Well, that's the best part. You guys get to decide.
-为什么那是最棒的  -我就不必决定了
- Why is that the best part? - I don't have to.
当然我们会帮你决定
Of course we'll help you decide.
我们会竭尽所能帮你
We'll do anything we can to help you.
大家举杯
I'd like to make a toast.
敬未来的钱德勒·宾太太
To the future Mrs. Chandler Bing...
我最好的朋友也是最善良的人
...my best friend and truly one of the nicest people that...
-我真的不要决定  -好吧
- Really not deciding. - Fine.
对不起  我不是故意要偷听的
Excuse me, I couldn't help overhearing.
-你要嫁给钱德勒宾  -对
- You're marrying Chandler Bing? - Yeah.
祝你好运
Good luck!
也祝你好运
Oh, and good luck to you too!
人多好啊
What a nice lady.
太棒了
Yeah!
-《虎胆龙威》还是很好看  -没错
- Die Hard, still great. - Yep.
再看一部
Let's make it a double feature?
你还租了什么
What else you rent?
《虎胆龙威2》
Die Hard 2.
乔伊  这也是《虎胆龙威1》
Joey, this is Die Hard 1 again.
我们再看一遍  就等于是《虎胆龙威2》了
Well, we'll watch it a second time and it's Die Hard 2.
-乔伊我们才看完  -所以呢
- Joey, we just saw it. - And?
再看一次就太好了
It would be cool to see it again!
-太棒了《虎胆龙威》 -《虎胆龙威》
- Yeah! Die Hard! - Die Hard!
兄弟  你没有说《虎胆龙威》
Dude, you didn't say Die Hard.
你还好吗
Is everything okay?
我还有事
Yeah, I just got plans.
约翰·麦克莱恩也有事要做[龙胆虎威主角]
Well, John McClane had plans.
我想在乔伊喝到兴起
I want to leave before Joey gets all worked up...
开始叫大家"贱人"前离开
...and starts calling everybody "Bitch."
你在胡说什么  贱人
What are you talking about, bitch?
-嘿  瑞秋  -什么事
- Hey, Rachel. - Yeah?
我结婚时  你愿意当我的首席伴娘吗
When I get married, will you be my maid of honor?
真的吗
Really?
我的天啊  菲比  我是说我
Oh, my God, Phoebe. I mean, I'm just...
慢着
Wait a minute.
如果我是你的首席伴娘  那表示你是莫妮卡的
If I'm your maid of honor, that means that you are Monica's.
如果你真的想那么做随便你
Well, if that's what you want.
想都别想菲比  我要当莫妮卡的首席伴娘
No way, Phoebe. I want to be Monica's.
为什么这件事这么重要
Why does it even matter?
你为什么觉得它很重要
Why does it matter to you?
因为她现在就要结婚了
Because this one is now.
我就只有两个最好的朋友
And it's two of our best friends.
谁知道你会嫁什么样的人
And who knows what you're gonna marry.
如果我嫁给罗斯呢  或乔伊
What if I marry Ross? Or Joey?
你不会的
You wouldn't.
瑞秋 我知道你真的想当莫妮卡的首席伴娘
Okay, look, Rachel. I know you really want to do this...
但我从来没有当过首席伴娘
...but I've never been maid of honor to anyone before.
我知道你至少当过两次伴娘
I know you've done it at least twice.
-对  但是菲比  -让我把话说完
- Yeah, but Phoebe... - Please let me finish.
我猜我已经说完了
I guess that was it.
好吧
Okay.
既然你没有当过伴娘
Since you've never done it before,
你可以当莫妮卡的首席伴娘
you can be Monica's maid of honor.
谢谢
Oh, thank you so much!
耶
Yay.
我一定会嫁给好男人
I'm gonna marry someone good.
我知道
Oh, I know.
比钱德勒还棒
Better than Chandler.
-发生了什么  -我不知道
- What happened? - I don't know.
我们睡着了  就这样
We fell asleep. That is all.
对  对吗  对
Yeah. Yeah? Yeah.
好了  我得走了
All right, well, I'd better go.
-我想那最好不过  -没错
- I think that would be best - Yeah.
-待会再聊  -好
- I'll talk to you later. - Okay.
-但千万别聊这件事  -没错  永远别提
- But not about this. - No, never. Never!
-再见  -别碰我
- Bye. - No touch. No touch.
我去吃早午餐时发生了一件怪事
Hey, a weird thing happened at brunch.
有个女人不经意听到我要嫁给你
This woman overheard that I was marrying you...
她跑来祝我好运
...and she wished me good luck.
真贴心
That's sweet.
不  更像是要说"瞧好吧您"
No, it was more like a "Good luck."
那个女人长什么样子
So, what did this woman look like?
她大概30岁  深色头发  很漂亮
She was, like, 30, dark hair, attractive.
你该不会是刚好看到一种
Any chance you were looking into a bright,
又亮又白的叫做镜子的东西吧
shiny thing called a mirror?
会是你大学时的女朋友吗
Was it someone you dated in college?
不在大学时  我只交过两个女朋友
No, I only dated two girls in college...
都是金发  都不漂亮
...both blond, both not attractive.
让我看看
Let me check this out.
-你在做什么  -来瞧瞧吧
- What are you doing? - Well, let's see.
是她吗
Okay, is that her?
天啊  是的
Oh, my God, yes!
-她是谁  -朱莉·格拉菲  夏令营女友
- Who is she? - Julie Graff, my camp girlfriend.
你和她分手了吗
Did you break up with her?
不  我们还在一起
No, we're still together.
我们交往了两个暑假  后来我跟她分手了
We went out for two summers and then I broke up with her.
-为什么  -第三年的暑假
- Why? - She came back the third summer...
她变得有一点肥
...and she'd gotten really fa...
-肥胖  -我没说肥胖
- Fat? - I did not say fat.
我是说肥
I said fa...
你只因为女生胖就跟她分手
You broke up with a girl because she was fat?
对
Yeah. Yeah.
但那真的是很久以前的事了 她还在难过吗
But it was a really long time ago. Does she still feel bad?
很明显是的
Apparently she does.
俗话说"大象很记仇"
You know what they say: "Elephants never forget."
说真的  和我结婚  祝你好运
Seriously, good luck marrying me.
怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
菲比是莫妮卡的首席伴娘
She's Monica's maid of honor.
希望会比上次你给楼下那个
Hope it goes better than the
姑娘当首席伴娘顺利
last time you did it for that girl downstairs.
你当过首席伴娘
You have been maid of honor before?
看吧  人就是不能说谎
You see? This is exactly why you shouldn't lie.
够了  我是首席伴娘
That's it. I am maid of honor.
-不  我才是  -为什么
- No, I am. - How come you are?
因为我在乎到不惜说慌
Because I cared enough to lie.
我可以帮你们决定  该由谁来当首席伴娘
Hey, I could help you decide who should do it.
试镜吧
We could have an audition.
看看你们当首席伴娘时会怎么处理突发状况
See how you'd handle maid-of-honor-type situations.
-你是什么意思  -我找工作的时候
- What do you mean? - When I want a job...
我会去试镜  如果他们觉得我是最棒的
...I audition and if I'm the best of the people they see...
我就可以演出
...I get the part.
试镜完  谁来决定首席伴娘人选
So, okay, so after this audition, who decides who gets it?
我跟罗斯可以当评审
Oh, me and Ross can be the judges.
-比让我们自己来决定好  -这太疯狂了
- It's better than us deciding. - Oh, this is crazy.
-扔个硬币决定不行吗  -不  硬币恨我
- Can't we just flip a coin? - No, coins hate me.
好  我们让罗斯跟乔伊来决定
Okay, fine. You know what? We will let Ross and Joey decide.
嗨
Hi!
罗斯  亲爱的
Ross, sweetie.
你好啊  大帅哥
Hey there, handsome thing.
这香水确实和阿玛尼的一样好啊
Wow, this cologne really is every bit as good as Giorgio.
嗨
Hey.
刚把你的电影拿回来
Just brought back your videos.
罗斯  我们得谈谈之前的事
Hey, Ross. Look, I think we need to talk about before.
才不要
No. No, we don't.
要的
Yes, we do.
那是我睡得最香甜的一觉
Now, look. That was the best nap I ever had.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
少来了  承认吧
Come on, admit it.
那是你睡过最香甜的一觉
That was the best nap you ever had.
我有过更棒的经验
I've had better.
好吧  什么时候
Okay. When?
好吧  那是我睡过最香甜的一觉
All right! All right! It was the best nap ever!
我承认  好吗
I said it, okay?
但那已经过去了  乔伊
But it's over, Joey!
我想再来一次
I want to do it again.
我们不能再来一次
We can't do it again.
-为什么  -因为那太诡异了
- Why not? - Because it's weird!
行吧
Fine.
想喝点东西吗
You want a drink?
-好啊  你有什么  -温牛奶跟抗组胺药
- Sure. What do you got - Warm milk and Excedrin PM.
钱德勒
Chandler.
我刚刚想到你是谁
I just figured out who you are.
你想到我在做什么吗
Can you figure out what I'm doing?
-你是路易斯·波森  -谁
- You're Louis Posen. - Who?
他是我五年级时最好的朋友
He was my best friend in fifth grade.
有一天我要他当我男朋友  他拒绝了
One day, I asked him to be my boyfriend and he said no.
你知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
因为他上厕所时
Because you kept talking to him
你一直在跟他说话
while he was trying to go to the bathroom?
因为她觉得我太肥...
No, but because he thought I was too fa...
每次想到这件事
Every time I think about it,
我都会和五年级时一样难过
it made me feel as bad as I was in fifth grade.
我真的觉得你该跟朱莉道歉
I really think you should apologize to Julie.
甜心你在开玩笑吗  那是十六年前的事
Honey, are you kidding? That was like 16 years ago.
如果路易斯能跟我道歉  我会觉得好过一点
It would make me feel better if Louis apologized to me.
好吧  但我警告你这会让我变成更好的人
I'll do it. But I warn you, this may make me a better person.
那可不是你爱上的那个男人
And that is not the man you fell in love with.
我们会假设突发状况来检验你们能否当首席伴娘
Okay, we'll give you hypothetical maid-of-honor situations.
计分范围从一分到十分
You'll be scored on a scale of one to ten.
-一分是最高分  -十分才是最高分
- One being the highest. - Ten is the highest.
-为什么十分是最高  -因为它最大
- Why is 10 the highest? - Because it's the highest.
好了  瑞秋  你先来
Okay, Rachel, you're up first.
一号突发状况  你跟莫妮卡在一起
Situation number one: You're with Monica.
婚礼就要开始了 莫妮卡想临阵脱逃
The wedding is about to start when Monica gets cold feet. Go!
我不想嫁给钱德勒
I don't want to marry Chandler.
-我想临阵逃脱  -没事的
- I've got cold feet. - It's gonna be okay.
跟一个男人共度一生  我不敢想
One man the rest of my life? I don't know.
这表示我永远都不能跟乔伊嘿咻了
This means I'll never get to sleep with Joey.
听着  莫妮卡
Look, Monica...
想临阵脱逃很正常·
...getting cold feet is very common.
因为期待太多
It's just because of all the anticipation.
记着你爱钱德勒
And you just have to remember that you love Chandler.
我也逃过婚
And also, I ran out on a wedding.
结婚礼物你可是留不住的
You don't get to keep the gifts.
切身体会  很好
Very good. Drawing on your own experience.
很好
Very good.
很好  瑞秋
Yes, very nice, Rachel.
谢谢评委
Thank you, judges.
-马屁精  -是吧
- Kiss ass. - Oh.
-菲比该你了  -是的  评委大人
- Okay, Phoebe. - Yes, Your Honor.
婚礼举行到一半
We're now in the ceremony.
莫妮卡就要说"我愿意"了
Monica is about to say, "I do"...
可是她的叔叔喝得烂醉 开始大吼大叫
...when her drunk uncle starts yelling.
你会怎么做  开始
What do you do? Go!
莫妮卡还小的时候
When Monica was a little girl...
我记得
...I remember that...
痛啊
Ow!
-非常好  -喔
- Very good! - Oh.
好极了  我给你满分
Yes, excellent. Perfect score.
她在婚礼中引起了骚乱
She just made a scene in the middle of the ceremony!
你想尝尝菲比的厉害吗
Hey, you want a little taste of Pheebs?
现在你们得以首席伴娘的身份祝贺新人
It is time for you to give your maid-of-honor speech.
我们还没有准备
We haven't even prepared...
-开始  -好吧
- Go! - Okay, okay, okay.
韦伯大辞典将婚姻定义为
Webster's Dictionary defines marriage as...
不重来  这贺词太烂了  我重来
Okay, no! Forget that! That sucks! Okay, never mind. Forget it.
我遇见我认识莫妮卡时
I met... I met Monica
我们只是六岁大的小女孩
when we were just a couple of 6-year-olds...
我在钱德勒25岁时和他成为了朋友
...and became friends with Chandler when he was 25...
虽然他就像六岁一样
...although he seemed like a 6-year-old.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
我看过他们单身跟交往时的样子
I've known them separately and together.
他们交往时
To know them as a couple
就是真爱的象征
is to know that you are in the presence of love.
现在我想举杯
So I would like to raise my glass...
敬莫妮卡跟钱德勒
...to Monica and Chandler...
和他们即将要携手共度的
...and the beautiful adventure
美好的冒险
they are about to embark upon together.
他们是世界上最坚定地要开展这段旅程的人了
I can think of no two people better prepared for the journey.
-说的好  -没错  真的很棒
- Great speech. - Yeah, it really was.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
菲比  该你了
Okay, Phoebe, I guess you're next.
虽然我觉得让你说是多余的
Although I really don't see the point.
好吧
Okay.
简直无法相信  莫妮卡和钱德勒要结婚了
I can't believe that Monica and Chandler are getting married.
我还记得我跟瑞秋聊过这一天得样子
I remember talking about this day with Rachel...
那时我们正在一起洗澡  一丝不挂
...while we were showering together, naked.
她突出了重围
And she's back in the game!
朱莉  你好
Julie. Hi.
钱德勒·宾  你记得我吧
Chandler Bing. I guess you remember me.
你好  逃兵
Hello, Skidmark.
昵称  待会解释
It's a nickname. I'll explain later.
挺明白的  不用解释
It's pretty clear.
我很早以前就该跟你道歉
I owe you a long, overdue apology.
我不该因为你的体重跟你分手
I shouldn't have broken up with you because of your weight.
那是你跟我分手的原因
That's why you broke up with me?
你不知道
You didn't know that?
看来我的任务已经达成
Well, I guess my work here is done.
但首先我要说
But first of all, I would like to say
你们两个都表现的很好
you both performed very well, okay?
你们应该觉得骄傲
You should be proud.
我还想说
And I'd also like to say,
在这场比赛里  没有人是输家
in this competition, there are no losers.
瑞秋除外  该死
Well, except Rachel. Damn it!
真的吗 我赢了
Really? I won.
-什么  -抱歉瑞秋  比分很接近
- What? - I'm sorry, Rach, it was really close.
我要求重新计算
Well, then I demand a recount!
其实也没有接近啦
Actually, it wasn't that close.
这次试镜本身就很蠢
You know what? Your thing was so stupid anyway.
投硬币决定  行吗
We're gonna flip a coin, all right?
头
Heads.
什么  硬币终于原谅我了
What? The coins have finally forgiven me!
我希望莫妮卡能够在你用你那
Know what? I hope Monica forgives you after you throw her...
素食主义怪力乱神的方式向她撒花之后原谅你
...vegetarian-voodoo-goddess-circle-y shower.
瑞秋  没事啦  你们最棒了
Rach, it's gonna be okay. You guys are the best!
当评审真的把我累坏了
Boy, I tell you. That judging stuff took a lot out of me.
-是吗  -没错
- Yeah? - Yeah.
上楼去我那里
Thinking about maybe going upstairs
在我沙发上睡个觉什么的吧
and taking a little nap on my couch.
和我有什么关系
Why would I care about that?
没关系啊  我就是说说
No reason. I'm just saying that...
我会在那
...that's where I'll be.
虽然结局不如预期中理想 但我很满意自己的表现
As bad as that went, I actually enjoyed myself.
我想我要为我做过的
I think that I'm going to apologize
所有蠢事道歉
for all the stupid things that I do.
你别做蠢事不就结了
Why don't you just stop doing stupid things?
你就不用道歉了
Then you wouldn't have to apologize.
我又能道歉又能做蠢事  多好
I'd love it if I could do both.
好了  我必须得问你
All right, I have to ask.
什么
What?
如果我变胖  你会和我分手吗
Will you break up with me if I get fat?
什么
What?
你和朱莉分手了  她重了多少
You broke up with Julie. How much weight did she gain?
145磅
A hundred and forty-five pounds.
在一年里
In one year?
天啊  她吃了什么  把全家人都吃了吗
My God, what did she eat? Her family?
那不是重点
That's not the point.
因为这个原因和人分手
I know it was a stupid reason
很愚蠢  但是我当时才15
to break up with someone, but I was 15.
不只十五岁的男孩觉得肥胖是个问题
Yeah, well, that's not the only time this was an issue.
你还记得你跟我们一起过感恩节的事吗
You remember when you spent Thanksgiving with us?
你也叫我胖子
You called me fat.
慢着
Wait a minute.
-那完全是另一回事  -怎么说
- That was totally different. - How?
你不该听到那句话  我是偷偷说的
You were not supposed to hear that. I said that behind your back.
那我怀孕了呢  我看起来会不同的
What if I have babies, okay? I'm gonna look different.
我能接受  但是我不知道你能否接受
I'm okay with that, but I'm not sure you are.
你得知道
You have to realize
我没觉得你是什么苗条的大美女
I don't think of you as a thin, beautiful woman.
我可以之后再给你道歉
This is one of the things that I can apologize for later.
我的意思是  你就是莫妮卡
What I mean is, you're Monica.
我爱的就是莫妮卡
Okay? And I am in love with Monica.
继续
Keep going.
你长胖也好  变矮也好
So you can balloon up or you can shrink down...
我都会深爱你
...and I will still love you.
就算我缩水到5厘米高也一样
Even if I were to shrink down to 2 inches tall?
我会把你装在口袋里
I'd carry you around in my pocket.
我爱你
I love you.
逃兵对姑娘还是很有一手嘛
Skidmark still got a way with the ladies.
嗨  菲比
Hi, Pheebs.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
我想道歉
I just want to apologize.
我真的很抱歉我太孩子气了
I'm really sorry I was a baby.
这太荒谬了瑞秋  我们都曾是孩子
That's ridiculous. Rachel, we were all babies once.
-你是说今天的事  -对
- Oh, you mean today. - Yeah.
你应该赢的
Yeah, and you know, you deserve to win.
我一直在想这件事
And I was thinking about it.
如果你是莫妮卡的首席伴娘  那我就是你的
If you're Monica's maid of honor, I get to be yours.
-对啊  -是
- Oh, yeah. - Yeah.
莫妮卡和钱德勒订婚时
When Monica and Chandler got engaged,
我收集了一些材料
I started to put some stuff together.
-以防万一  -你太好了  谢谢
- Just in case. - Oh, that's so sweet. Thanks.
我知道莫妮卡很喜欢这本诗集
Here is a book of poetry that I know Monica loves.
天啊  这真有趣  你看
Oh, God, this is funny. Look.
这是一年万圣节
Here's a picture from one Holloween
她打扮成新娘的样子
where she dressed up as a bride.
她要我帮她拉裙摆
She made me carry her train...
那真的很奇怪  因为我扮的是神力女超人
...which was weird because I was Wonder Woman.
我还发现了个小包包
Oh, and here's a little purse that I found.
我想他们能把戒指放在这里面
I just thought they could hold the rings in there.
-哦  -还有
- Oh. - And...
复古式手帕
...vintage handkerchiefs,
人们总在婚礼上泪流满面
you know, because people cry at weddings.
我就要用个几条
I'm just gonna grab a couple of these.
这手绢真不错
This stuff is great.
我都忘了这个了
I forgot this was in here.
这是我留下来要在自己婚礼上用的吊袜带
This was the garter that I was saving for my wedding.
莫妮卡可以拿这个当"借别人的东西"
And I wanted it to be Monica's "Something borrowed."
还是蓝色的
And it's blue.
瑞秋  我觉得你应该当首席伴娘
Rach, I think that you should be Monica's maid of honor.
是吗
You do?
-为什么  -因为这对你来说意义更加重大
- Why? - Because I think it means more to you.
但菲比  你赢了比赛
But, Pheebs, honey, you earned it.
没事  我是说  这可是自你
It's fine. I mean, this is something...
14岁以来的梦想啊
...that you've been thinking about since you were, what, 14?
我才十岁  发育早而已
No, I was 10. I just developed early.
天啊
Man alive!
-嗨  都好吗  -嗨
- Hey, what's going on? - Hey!
我们刚刚决定瑞秋会是你的首席伴娘
We decided Rachel is going to be your maid of honor.
太好了
Oh, that's great!
太棒了  我们得开始计划
Oh, wow. Okay, we really have to start planning.
我有好多点子
I have really specific ideas.
一周见四次吧
We should meet four times a week.
上班前来我家
Come to my place, we'll get together before work.
早上六点半怎么样  我家  太激动了
What do you say, 6:30, my place? So excited!
好  你现在笑了
Yeah, okay. You laugh now.
她是你的了
She's gonna be yours.
睡得真香啊
Great nap.
是啊
It really was.
你这都是在干什么  兄弟
What the hell are you doing?
天啊
God!
失陪
Excuse me.